<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>DevSlant</title><link href="http://devslant.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://devslant.com/feeds/learning.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://devslant.com/</id><updated>2014-08-27T19:14:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Learning How To Learn</title><link href="http://devslant.com/learning-how-to-learn.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-08-27T19:14:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Derek Rodger</name></author><id>tag:devslant.com,2014-08-27:learning-how-to-learn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just a short note, if you're here to review the Learning How to Learn Assignment #2, please take a look at:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://devslant.com/blog/2014/08/21/a-mind-for-learning/"&gt;A Mind for Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://devslant.com/blog/2014/08/23/space-dot-dot-dot-the-final-frontier/"&gt;Space...The Final Frontier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://devslant.com/blog/2014/08/23/un-focussed/"&gt;Stay on Target&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://devslant.com/blog/2014/08/25/pomodoro/"&gt;You say tomato, I say pomodoro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>"You say tomato, I say pomodoro"</title><link href="http://devslant.com/you-say-tomato-i-say-pomodoro.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-08-25T13:14:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Derek Rodger</name></author><id>tag:devslant.com,2014-08-25:you-say-tomato-i-say-pomodoro.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="top" alt='pomodoro' src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/7133191/pomodoro-timer11.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever find yourself with a project or task to do, but not the motivation to start?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It becomes easy to find distractions doesn't it? You're brain is trying to find ways to avoid the small amount of displeasure it experiences getting started on something, especially something difficult. But there are ways to encourage your brain. Let's focus on the Pomodoro Technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pomodoro Technique is a time management method developed by Francesco Cirillo. The idea is to use a timer, and work for 25 minutes and then take a small break, where you reward yourself. The reward is important, because it gives you motivation and encouragement for getting through the 25 minutes of uninterrupted focus. The method is based on the idea that frequent breaks can improve mental agility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="top" alt='pomodoro flow' src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/7133191/Pomodoro_flow.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After four pomodoro sessions, take a longer break after the fourth one. Thirty minutes is the usual recommendation. Now this doesn't mean to stop working. Instead switch to another task, now check your emails or arrange those meetings that you avoided while you were in your pomodori.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find this technique particularly useful at work. I can determine which task I am going to work on, set a timer on the computer, and focus on it - no email, no news feeds - just concentration on the problem at hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Citations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Article: wikipedia. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki.Pomodoro_Technique"&gt;Pomodoro Technique&lt;/a&gt;. Wikipedia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>"Stay on Target"</title><link href="http://devslant.com/stay-on-target.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-08-23T10:37:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Derek Rodger</name></author><id>tag:devslant.com,2014-08-23:stay-on-target.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="top" alt="stay on target" src="http://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/7133191/stay-on-target-achieve-goals.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you're eager to learn, you have passion for a subject, all you need to do is dive in, spend eight hours a day learning it, and you'll be an expert, right? Not quite... As I mentioned in the last article about Spaced Repetition, your brain needs time to actually grow and link the neural pathways that will store information. It's not just spacing between reviews that you need. You need to unfocus to learn too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;(Un)focussed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="top" alt="focus" src="http://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/7133191/internet-marketing-business.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can I learn faster if I'm not focused?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's not that you don't focus, it's that you don't try to spend all your time focused. Focus is still needed, it's how we initially get the information into our brains. Concentrating, absorbing information, really applying your mind on something challenging is strengthening your mind. But like building muscles, you need to rest, because that's when the actual gains are made.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever notice that when you are working on a difficult problem, and you go for a walk, or maybe a drive, or just do something that takes your mind off what you were working on, that you suddenly have an idea pop into your head that solves the problem? Wouldn't it be great if that happened more often? What you want is to relax your mind in what's called diffuse mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Diffusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="top" alt="stay on target" src="http://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/7133191/Blausen_0315_diffusion.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is diffuse mode, and what's happening when your in it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diffuse mode occurs when you are not concentrating (focusing) on something in particular. It's when you are relaxed, and able to think about things from a high-level, rather than buried amongst the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how does diffuse mode help?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are in this mode of thinking, your brain is still working on the problem, but now that your not focussed on the details, your brain is able to start connecting what you're learning with other knowledge you already have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"If you are grappling with a new concept or trying to solve a new problem, you don't have preexisting neural patterns to help guide your thoughts"&lt;/em&gt; - Barbara Oakley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is when diffuse mode helps. It pulls together knowledge you have with the information you are learning, combining them in new ways. When you are focused on something, diffuse mode is blocked. By taking a break (say, every 25 minutes, which I'll talk about in another post), you allow the diffuse mode to take over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Citations&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book: Barbara Oakley. ISBN:039916524X. A Mind For Numbers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>"Space...The Final Frontier"</title><link href="http://devslant.com/spacethe-final-frontier.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-08-23T10:29:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Derek Rodger</name></author><id>tag:devslant.com,2014-08-23:spacethe-final-frontier.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="top" alt="Space" src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/7133191/space-637x398.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing from my last post about &lt;a href="https://class.coursera.org/learning-001" target="_blank"&gt;Learning How to Learn&lt;/a&gt;, this time I want to turn my focus to another effective technique for recalling and reviewing information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Spaced repetition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people, when learning something make the mistake of attempting to learn it all at once ('cramming'). I've been guilty of doing this in the past :-). I'm a fast reader, and I used to retain a fair amount of what I read on the first past (or at least, *I* thought so). This may allow you to hold onto the information long enough to recall it shortly afterwards, but for true, deep understanding, it's a poor way to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="top" alt="cramming" src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/7133191/cramming-cramming-everywhere.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your brain needs time to create the neurological connections, to grow the new dendrites after learning. This doesn't happen all at once, so trying to stuff everything into your brain in one session won't work. You're just overfilling your working memory. So what is a good technique for learning something, for really understanding it in depth?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forcing yourself to remember something, almost relearning it, after a gap or 'space' from when you first learned it is very useful for improving. Spaced repetition is the idea that if you review material at different intervals, ranging from minutes after you first learned it, to days, weeks, even months, then you will have stored it permanently and will be able to recall it with ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you want to do is go from the short time - for example: reading a page of a book, then closing it and attempting to recall what that page was about, to writing down what you recall and understand about the material later that same day, to then recalling the material a few days later, and then extending that out to many days/weeks/months later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use flash cards to help you review, or if you prefer software, there is &lt;a href="http://ankisrs.net/"&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt;, which is spaced repetition software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This works because you want to practice recalling the information not just the moment after you have read/watched/heard something, but again &lt;strong&gt;just before&lt;/strong&gt; you are about to forget it. Practicing like this at spaced intervals allows you to extend how long you retain the information, and increases your understandng. Your neural pathways expand, make more connections, and can lead you to being more creative as you see other uses and related ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Citations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Article: Derek Sivers. &lt;a href="http://sivers.org/srs"&gt;Memorizing a programming language using spaced repetition software&lt;/a&gt;. Derek Sivers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Article: Gary Wolf. &lt;a href="http://quantifiedself.com/2012/06/spaced-repetition-and-learning/"&gt;Spaced Repetition and Learning&lt;/a&gt;. Quantified Self&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Article: wikipedia. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spaced_repetition"&gt;Spaced Repetition&lt;/a&gt;. Wikipedia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="repetition"></category></entry><entry><title>"A Mind for Learning"</title><link href="http://devslant.com/a-mind-for-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-08-21T05:55:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Derek Rodger</name></author><id>tag:devslant.com,2014-08-21:a-mind-for-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="left" alt="Brain" src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/7133191/r4_light-brain.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I began an online course through &lt;a href="https://coursera.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://class.coursera.org/learning-001" target="_blank"&gt;Learning How to Learn&lt;/a&gt;. I've been interested in advances in neuroscience for awhile, and some of that field has concentrated on trying to understand how people learn, what works, and what doesn't. Learning How to Learn, taught by Dr. Barbara Oakley and Dr. Terrence Sejnowski brings together the latest information in the field. Using clear explanations and examples, they have put together a four-week course that provides incredibly useful techniques for improving your learning and deepening your understanding of topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this course, there is an assignment to help deepen your understanding of the material by explaining and educating others about some of the topics in the course. This blog post (and some future ones) is part of that assignment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Teaching as Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd heard the phrase "The best way to learn something is to teach it" before, but is it true? And if so, why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"While we teach, we learn", said Roman philosopher Seneca. What is now called the "protege effect", students who taught others scored higher on tests than those learning on their own. Teaching forces you to work harder to understand the material, allowing you to recall it more accurately and apply it more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, the very act of writing this blog post, recalling information from the course and other sources and attempting to explain it helps increase my &lt;strong&gt;own&lt;/strong&gt; understanding of the topic. Attempting to recall and explain something strengthens the neurological connections in the brain. Improving through teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Citations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Article: Frank Oppenheimer. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frank_Oppenheimer"&gt;"the best way to learn is to teach"&lt;/a&gt;. wikipedia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Article: Anne Murphy Paul. &lt;a href="ideas.time.com/2011/11/30/the-protege-effect/"&gt;"The Protege Effect"&lt;/a&gt;. Time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Article: Kendra Cherry. &lt;a href="http://psychology.about.com/od/educationalpsychology/tp/effective-learning.htm"&gt;"How to Become a More Effective Learner"&lt;/a&gt;. About.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="numbers"></category><category term="chunking"></category><category term="diffuse"></category><category term="deliberate practice"></category></entry><entry><title>"Time for a Change"</title><link href="http://devslant.com/time-for-a-change.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-30T00:06:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Derek Rodger</name></author><id>tag:devslant.com,2013-01-30:time-for-a-change.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
    The first, and obvious: a new blog layout. In fact, I am moving this blog to github (and will change devslant.com to point to it shortly).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    In addition, I've decided not to keep all the previous blog posts, though they could be imported fairly easily.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
    Career Change
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    This week marks the first week I am no longer at &lt;a href="http://corp.airg.com"&gt;airG&lt;/a&gt;. It was a great run over 8 years (with ups and downs), but now I am looking for a new adventure! And if anything, the field of software development has only gotten more exciting.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    Last year was when I really took an interest in the whole nosql area, along with node.js. This year is MOAR! I expect Perl is not what I will end up working with any longer, at least not for a majority of the software most companies want developed.The JVM-based languages look really interesting, I recently picked up 'Land of Lisp', and may even do some old-school C again. I find more and more that I want to know the features of most languages, and be able to use a mix, with a concentration of one or two.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    As an example of the awesome things to progress further with (and I will blog about):
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.datastax.com/" title="CassandraDB" target="_blank"&gt;CassandraDB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.couchbase.com/" title="Couchbase" target="_blank"&gt;Couchbase 2.x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.foundationdb.com/" title="FoundationDB" target="_blank"&gt;FoundationDB&lt;a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.elasticsearch.org/" title="elasticsearch" target="_blank"&gt;elasticsearch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://logstash.net/" title="logstash" target="_blank"&gt;logstash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://storm-project.net/" title="Storm real-time computation" target="_blank"&gt;Storm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://zookeeper.apache.org/" title="ZooKeeper" target="_blank"&gt;ZooKeeper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
    &lt;li&gt;Virtualization&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;M2M (Machine-to-Machine)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    There are also several key papers that I have been reading (and will blog these too):
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://vldb.org/pvldb/vol5/p1771_georgelee_vldb2012.pdf" title="Unified Logging Infrastructure for Data Analytics at Twitter" target="_blank"&gt;Unified Logging Infrastructure for Data Analytics at Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://paperhub.s3.amazonaws.com/dace52a42c07f7f8348b08dc2b186061.pdf" title="Volcano - An Extensible and Parallel Query Evaluation System" target="_blank"&gt;Volcano - An Extensible and Parallel Query Evaluation System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amundsen.com/downloads/sagas.pdf" title="Sagas" target="_blank"&gt;Sagas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://static.googleusercontent.com/external_content/untrusted_dlcp/research.google.com/en//archive/bigtable-osdi06.pdf" title="Bigtable: A Distributed Storage System for Structured Data" target="_blank"&gt;Bigtable: A Distributed Storage System for Structured Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/AllThingsDistributed/sosp/amazon-dynamo-sosp2007.pdf" title="Dynamo: Amazon's Highly Available Key-value Store" target="_blank"&gt;Dynamo: Amazon's Highly Available Key-value Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    There are many others of course, this is just part of my initial list.
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="airG"></category><category term="job"></category><category term="learning"></category></entry></feed>