<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>DevSlant</title><link href="http://devslant.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://devslant.com/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://devslant.com/</id><updated>2013-10-02T21:46:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>"Deep dives and treading water"</title><link href="http://devslant.com/deep-dives-and-treading-water.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-02T21:46:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Derek Rodger</name></author><id>tag:devslant.com,2013-10-02:deep-dives-and-treading-water.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="top" alt="eRezLife Logo" src=http://www.erezlife.com/images/topbar.gif&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting from scratch, it's something developers should be used to...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago, I started a new job at &lt;a href="http://www.erezlife.com" target="_blank"&gt;eRezLife&lt;/a&gt;. I consider myself fortunate to have landed in a small company where I can make an impact, and each and every person is great to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what's so deep about that? We're just starting to migrate from a PHP code base (that's where I'm treading at the moment) to Python + Django where I will be diving in as deep as I can, along with learning more JavaScript and jQuery. I've spent 8½ years working with Perl (with the last few years spent in modern Perl with Moose). I can truly say I am happy for a change, and really want to absorb the concepts within Python, not just the syntax and some libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Completely unrelated to programming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought a new road bike. I've ridden the same bike for nearly 8 years, and it's just not comfortable. Trust me when I say, get a bike fitting before you buy a bike. Plus the technology in bikes has improved quite a bit during this time, and the carbon fiber in the frames these days is incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="left" alt="Trek Domane" src=https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/7133191/Trek_Domane.png width="600"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my new ride. Why yes, that &lt;b&gt;is&lt;/b&gt; a &lt;a href="http://www.trekbikes.com/ca/en/projectone#model/domane6series" target="_blank"&gt;ProjectOne&lt;/a&gt; bike :-). This pic is really what it looks like, since ProjectOne lets you customize the parts and colors. Part of my plan for next year is to ride in some of the Gran Fondo's (Grand Rides). Either (or both):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rbcgranfondowhistler.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Whistler Gran Fondo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.granfondoaxelmerckx.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Axel Merckx Gran Fondo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the few rides I've had before the weather turned to heavy rain, I can already tell that the fit is sooo much better. No back ache, neck pain or headaches. And it's &lt;b&gt;fast&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="php"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="django"></category><category term="erezlife"></category><category term="domane"></category><category term="trek"></category><category term="granfondo"></category></entry></feed>